<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How to deploy and scale a Dapp</title><link>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/</link><description>Recent content on How to deploy and scale a Dapp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to build a scalable dapp</title><link>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/intro/</guid><description>How to build a scalable Dapp ETHDenver 2023
Agenda Who is this talk for?
About me
What is a Dapp?
What are the components of a Dapp?
How to deploy the components.
How to design for scale.
Wrapping it up
Link to the slides somewhere on the page. Maybe QR code too
Who is this talk for? Anybody building a Dapp Somebody that wants to deploy to an EVM chain About Me Alex Norell</description></item><item><title>What is a Dapp?</title><link>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/what_is_a_dapp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/what_is_a_dapp/</guid><description>What is a Dapp? Onchain Smart contracts Assets Data Off Chain Compute Assets Data What are the components of a Dapp? Frontend
Backend
Smart Contract
Frontend UI for App Wallet Interface Usually a website Display data from chain Backend Blockchain Data Other Data Computation Write data to the chain Smart Contracts How your application actually interacts with the chain Transactions to your contracts Read information from your contract</description></item><item><title>Deploy a Dapp</title><link>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/deploy_a_dapp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/deploy_a_dapp/</guid><description>Which chain should I deploy to? Ethereum (Mainnet) L2s Arbitrum Optimism Alt-L1 Polygon Avalanche BNB Chain Gnosis Fantom Metis Where do I deploy offchain? Hyperscaler AWS GCP Azure Scaler Linode DigitalOcean Virtuozzo Bare Metal In you basement In a colocation</description></item><item><title>Dapp Design Decisions</title><link>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/dapp_design_decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/dapp_design_decisions/</guid><description>Design decisions Requirements Keep costs reasonable Handle all the traffic Prevent abuse Other Sanctions Censorship resistance Cost What should go on chain? Onchain:
User interactions Transfer of ownership Material change of state Offchain:
Binary blobs Where do I get my data? Subgraphs Nodes Partners (APIs) Subgraphs GraphQL Query events from the blockchain Pay for your queries with crypto Reliable, but not infallible Nodes What you need them for? Node Types Dedicated Shared Public Node Providers Chainstack Quicknode Ankr Alchemy Datahub Blockdaemon Partners Get pre-formatted data directly from APIs Accelerate development Potentially better data accuracy</description></item><item><title>Wrapping it up</title><link>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/conclusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.github.io/ethdenver-how-to-build-a-scalable-dapp/conclusion/</guid><description>Wrapping it up Odos Odos.xyz DEX Aggregator 6 Chains Unique Smart Order Routing Just Launched an API Socials and Slides website: alexnorell.com github: alexnorell twitter: @alexnorell ens: alexnorell.eth telegram: alexnorell slides: ethdenver.alexnorell.com</description></item></channel></rss>